William A. Wilsnagh

Managing Director / CEO

wilsnaghw@gmail.com

Summary

An accomplished CxO and strategic leader of people from diverse backgrounds across multiple continents with experience as intellectual owner of complex change management solutions. Very strong skills and expertise within the Gaming/Gambling, Information Technology, IT Security and Software Solution (SaaS) industry - within diverse businesses that include start-ups, SME's and listed global organisations. I have played a key role taking some of these business through transformational change and sustainable growth.

Through these various leadership roles I have been able to make use of my passion for technology and innovation, along with the unique skill of applying these to strategic business purposes.

I excel in building, leading and coaching dynamic and diverse teams of people, across multiple locations and continents. I'm particularly excited about the future of IoT & Cyber Security and to be part of the digital transformation era.

Specialities: Commercial Leadership, Software Product Development, Operational Management, Organisational Development, Sale & Financial Performance, Product Management, Customer Engagement, Business Strategy, Business Development, Operations, Transformation, Business Integration.

Experience

COO / CEO at BetStone (powered by Microgaming)

May 2012 - Present (4 years 11 months)

Initially GM / COO and then CEO of this international technology and systems group of companies. Instigated strategy, extending to a new geographical market 300% larger than previous for a new business within the group, utilising my extensive industry and geographical knowledge, doubling the business potential.

Turned around software development teams & roadmap to strategically plan & redirect development & delivery of a software & hardware product portfolio for new vibrant markets.

Strategy planning and execution for improving market-share and financial performance in North & South America and European markets concentrating on innovative marketing & commercial models, product development, analysing competitor offerings and monitoring emerging technology.

Managed, mentored and coached multidisciplinary management teams including finance, sales, marketing, administration and technical support.

Engaging with certification laboratories re compliance and industry technical standards for the various jurisdictions. Called extensively on my IT Security advisory services, business information protection, data security, risk and compliance experience to set up the USA operations in a secure way.

Led strategic negotiations and product licencing with 3rd Party software providers.

Managing Director - Europe & Africa at Aristocrat

March 2007 - April 2012 (5 years 2 months)

Led the African & European businesses as a key member of the Global Leadership Team, responsible for strategic plan development and execution for the region for this listed technology and systems supplier.

Achieved and exceeded targets & increase revenue to over 10% year on year.

Introduced innovative sales models, administered marketing strategies & negotiated large sales opportunities 1:1 with strategic customers.

Turned around under-performing entity from 11% decline in sales to an increase of 40% within 14 months of taking over territory

Increased ship-share by 10% to maintain no: 1 market position.

Introduced innovative new services to enable improved customer satisfaction.

Devised innovative Sales & Operations planning process increasing forecast accuracy & demand management therefore increasing working capital.

Set up a local R&D software development team to increase turnaround of software updates to customers, reducing downtime and securing a further 3 years of revenue.

Director - Software Solutions & Information Security at Altech NamITech - Software Solutions & Information Security company

May 2001 - March 2007 (5 years 11 months)

Positions held: Dir: Software Solutions & Information Security ('06-'07), Dir: Technology Services & Operations ('03-'06), MD: Gaming & Leisure ('01-'03)

Joined as one of four market focused business unit Directors, to refocus & grow this technology division of Nampak (Nampak IT Technologies, later sold to Altech - part of the Altron Group of Companies).

Understood the business of the Information Security and Mobile Technologies extremely well ensuring that the services offered was fit for the business.

Managed key client relationships, offering:- Information Security Consulting, Services, Policy Development & Risk Assessments specifically Software Solutions, Information Security & Smartcard Solutions.

In secure manufacturing systems dramatically increased MasterCard & Visa service delivery, saved 2 strategic accounts.

CIO (Chief Information Officer) / Executive Director: Information Technology at Tsogo Sun (MGM Grand RSA)

July 1998 - April 2001 (2 years 10 months)

Hotels and Casinos company employing 1000 with an annual turnover of \$100m+

Developed & implemented IT strategy for all temporary and permanent Casinos and Resorts countrywide, including the flagship operation MonteCasino.

Project management of IT Vendors and Contractors.

Stayed abreast of new IT Technologies and trends with a hands-on approach, and travelled abroad extensively researching suitable systems & technology.

Systems Manager at IGT

March 1996 - June 1998 (2 years 4 months)

Technical Manager at Norma Botha & Associates

September 1992 - February 1996 (3 years 6 months)

Languages

English

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

Afrikaans

(Professional working proficiency)

Skills & Expertise

Strategy

Leadership

Executive Management

New Business Development

Start-ups

International Business Strategy

Customer Service

Product Development

Coaching & Mentoring

Management

Entrepreneurship

Risk Management

Budgets

Product Management

Strategic Negotiations

Strategic Planning

Pre-sales

Innovative Problem Solver

Enterprise Software

Operations Management

IT Strategy

Account Management

Software Development

Business Development

Business Intelligence

Consulting

Sales Management

Manufacturing

Telecommunications

Networking

Project Management

Team Management

Analysis

CRM

Information Technology

Business Process Improvement

Business Process Re-engineering

Business Strategy

Education

Leeds Beckett University

MSc, Information Systems, 2000 - 2003

Grade: Masters

Interests

MotoGP, F1, Rugby, Man United

William A. Wilsnagh

Managing Director / CEO

wilsnaghw@gmail.com



7 people have recommended William A.

"I have known William for a couple of years and I can honestly say he is always ready to listen, give advice and recommendations. He has the ability to help grow any business through his use of market knowledge and contacts within the Gaming industry. He is easy to work with, reliable, trustworthy and able to easily work with anyone. I had the pleasure of working with William on a number of contracts, and have found his insight into the gaming sector is only surpassed by his ability to bring the right people together for the good of the project. He has strong relationship building skills allied to a clear understanding of the technical side. He is someone you enjoy doing business with and I would wholeheartedly recommend."

— **Jaime Riera**, *Founding Partner*, *RIERA Y CARRERAS ASOCIADOS*, was with another company when working with William A. at Aristocrat

"I have known William for many years and he has always been honest, reliable and someone that will go the extra mile. In all the years we have done business together I have known him to be well versed about all the products he has supplied and always willing to ensure we got the service and back-up we require in our highly competitive industry."

— Billy Gray, was William A.'s client

"William is a dedicated team leader committed to the personal development of his staff in achieving corporate objectives. At the same time he is an astute business manager committed to achieving financial objectives."

— Claudius van Wyk, was a consultant or contractor to William A. at Aristocrat

"William is a mature manager with the capability to stay calm, yet focused, under extreme conditions. He worked for me when we had to restructure NamiTech and his insightful understanding of very complex issues assisted tremendously in getting this difficult and sensitive job done. Post the restructuring he played a fundamental role in getting the business back on track. I would employ William any day again. Wessie vd Westhuizen"

— Wessie Van Der Westhuizen, managed William A. at Altech NamlTech - Software Solutions & Information Security company

"I have known William for the past 10 years and was his colleague for 5 years at Namitech. William is one of the most dedicated, trustworthy and professional individuals that I have worked with. He leads from the front and manage to inspire colleagues and business partners to achieve their goals. William is passionate about technology and innovation and has a unique skill to apply these for strategic business purposes. I highly recommend him."

— **Christi Maherry**, worked indirectly for William A. at Altech NamlTech - Software Solutions & Information Security company

"As a Director of Software Solutions & Information Security, William understood the Business of the Gaming, Mobile Technologies and Information Security extremely well ensuring that the service offered was fit for the Business. Williams in depth knowledge in these industries was easily translated into Business Goals. William always had a clear strategic focus in a diverse Technology portfolio. It was a pleasure to work with William. His Leadership encouraged teamwork through motivation and recognition."

— **Bruce Anderson**, reported to William A. at Altech NamITech - Software Solutions & Information Security company

"William was responsible for the IT function of Tsogo Sun - a hotel/ casino group in South Africa. William handled his resposibilities in a commendable manner and directed the department in an efficient and professional way. I would recommend William unreservedly"

— **Ken Rosevear**, managed William A. indirectly at Tsogo Sun (MGM Grand RSA)

Contact William A. on LinkedIn